Hi, my name is Anthony Boyko and I will be talking about the remaining four papers in the vision transformers lecture that my partner and you just started talking about.
안녕하세요, 제 이름은 Anthony Boyko입니다. 저는 제 파트너와 여러분이 방금 이야기하기 시작한 비전 트랜스포머 강의의 나머지 4개 논문에 대해 이야기할 것입니다.
The 1st, being emerging properties and self-supervised vision transformers, it focuses on self distillation with no labels. Also called Dino as the proposed model in this paper.
첫 번째는 신흥 자산이자 자체 감독 비전 변환기로서 라벨이 없는 자체 증류에 중점을 둡니다. 본 논문에서 제안하는 모델은 Dino라고도 한다.
It is a self-supervised approach to vision transformers and it builds upon.
이는 비전 변환기에 대한 자체 감독 방식이며 이를 기반으로 합니다.
Diet and highlights the success of canaries neighbors without additional fine tuning under the few stipulations and needs a momentum encoder and multi crop augmentation. I'll discuss about those later in the presentation.
몇 가지 규정에 따라 추가 미세 조정 없이 이웃 카나리아의 성공을 다이어트하고 강조하며 운동량 인코더와 다중 작물 확대가 필요합니다. 이에 대해서는 나중에 프레젠테이션에서 논의하겠습니다.
Self distillation with no labels.
라벨이 없는 자가 증류입니다.
What is it? So I'm going to 1st start by just getting a very brief overview.
그것은 무엇입니까? 그래서 저는 아주 간략한 개요를 살펴보는 것으로 첫 번째 시작을 하려고 합니다.
Of what it is, and then I'll add so go on. It will be more and more in depth. So imagine an input image X.
그것이 무엇인지, 이어서 덧붙이겠습니다. 점점 더 깊이 있게 될 것입니다. 입력 이미지 X를 상상해 보세요.
We're going to generate a pair of rent of views X 1 and X 2. So these are some random transformation. Imagine we rotate the image.
우리는 한 쌍의 뷰 X 1과 X 2를 생성할 것입니다. 따라서 이것은 임의의 변환입니다. 이미지를 회전한다고 상상해 보세요.
Crop it, blur it, things of that nature.
자르고, 흐리게 하고, 그런 성격의 것들을 말이죠.
We're going to input them into the network G beta.
우리는 그것들을 네트워크 G 베타에 입력할 것입니다.
In this case, the diagram is showing where there's 1 student 1 teacher.
이 경우 다이어그램은 학생 1명, 교사 1명이 있는 곳을 보여줍니다.
Denoted by the S and T, respectively, but you could have more students.
각각 S와 T로 표시되지만 더 많은 학생을 가질 수도 있습니다.
We're going to make a prediction as shown by the soft max.
우리는 소프트 맥스에 표시된 대로 예측을 할 것입니다.
And then we're going to use the probabilities to calculate the loss where the loss function is just the cross entropy.
그런 다음 확률을 사용하여 손실 함수가 교차 엔트로피인 손실을 계산하겠습니다.
And then we update the weights a few things that you'll notice here is the teacher is influenced by this exponential moving average by the students. I'll explain the purpose of that later.
그런 다음 가중치를 업데이트합니다. 여기에서 알 수 있는 몇 가지 사항은 교사가 학생들의 지수 이동 평균에 영향을 받는다는 것입니다. 그 목적에 대해서는 나중에 설명하겠습니다.
And that's what the stands for exponential moving average. There's a centering operation stop dimension collapse in the teacher network.
이것이 지수 이동 평균의 약자입니다. 교사 네트워크에 센터링 작업 중지 차원 붕괴가 있습니다.
And then also because we don't really want
그리고 우리가 별로 원하지 않기 때문에
The teacher to be learning from this from its prediction. We have this stop gradient. So it's values don't update.
교사는 예측을 통해 이를 학습합니다. 정지 경사도가 있습니다. 따라서 값이 업데이트되지 않습니다.
So, first, we'll go over the network cost function. Like, what are we actually trying to accomplish here? Well, we're given a global set of views, X and a local set of views X 1.
먼저 네트워크 비용 함수에 대해 살펴보겠습니다. 예를 들어, 우리가 여기서 실제로 달성하려는 것은 무엇입니까? 글쎄, 우리는 전역 뷰 집합 X와 로컬 뷰 집합 X 1을 받았습니다.
Our X prime, sorry, we wish to minimize the cross entropy loss, which is denoted by L under subscript C this multi crop component of the architecture.
X 소수입니다. 죄송합니다. 교차 엔트로피 손실을 최소화하고 싶습니다. 이는 아키텍처의 다중 자르기 구성 요소인 아래 첨자 C 아래 L로 표시됩니다.
Has the author uses or this is the multi crop component of the architecture. The author uses to global views at 224 squared and 96 squared.
저자가 사용했거나 이것이 아키텍처의 다중 자르기 구성 요소입니다. 저자는 224 제곱 및 96 제곱의 전역 보기를 사용합니다.
So, these are a small and a large image.
그래서 이것은 작은 이미지와 큰 이미지입니다.
Global views are large parts of the original image. Imagine something greater than 50% and local views are small patches.
전역 보기는 원본 이미지의 큰 부분입니다. 50%보다 큰 것을 상상해 보세요. 로컬 뷰는 작은 패치입니다.
We want to minimize the two views or minimize the loss between the two views using this cross entropy loss. So between the global view and the local views. So that's what the way you're trying to minimize the difference between.
우리는 이 교차 엔트로피 손실을 사용하여 두 뷰를 최소화하거나 두 뷰 간의 손실을 최소화하려고 합니다. 따라서 전역 보기와 로컬 보기 사이에 있습니다. 그래서 이것이 차이점을 최소화하려는 방법입니다.
And you can see the first summation is all of the local views within the set and the local views do not equal the global views. And then you go over all of the different global views.
그리고 첫 번째 합계는 세트 내의 모든 로컬 뷰이고 로컬 뷰는 글로벌 뷰와 동일하지 않음을 알 수 있습니다. 그런 다음 다양한 글로벌 관점을 모두 검토합니다.
Unlike knowledge distillation, there's no priority for the teacher. So this is where we solve this by using previous iterations from the students to make that priority. And this is the momentum encoder.
지식 증류와 달리 교사에게 우선순위는 없습니다. 그래서 우리는 학생들의 이전 반복을 사용하여 우선순위를 정함으로써 이 문제를 해결합니다. 그리고 이것은 운동량 인코더입니다.
The exponential moving average is how this momentum encoder works. And it's based on these previous iterations on how the teacher network updates its weights.
지수 이동 평균은 이 운동량 인코더가 작동하는 방식입니다. 이는 교사 네트워크가 가중치를 업데이트하는 방법에 대한 이전 반복을 기반으로 합니다.
Because when you initialize the model, both networks are going to be started at like random weights. And so how do we update the teacher.
모델을 초기화하면 두 네트워크 모두 동일한 임의 가중치로 시작되기 때문입니다. 그러면 교사를 어떻게 업데이트합니까?
If we have no basis, we do that based on the student and then the students will learn from now this updated teacher.
근거가 없다면 학생을 기반으로 그렇게 하고 학생들은 이제 이 업데이트된 교사로부터 배울 것입니다.
So the value of this is some parameter lambda, which is just basically how much are we keeping from the original teacher network. And then the inverse of that value between the students.
따라서 이것의 값은 일부 매개변수 람다입니다. 이는 기본적으로 원래 교사 네트워크에서 얼마나 많은 것을 유지하고 있는지를 나타냅니다. 그리고 학생들 사이의 그 가치의 역수입니다.
So this is just basically how much are we keeping from the original teacher network and then the inverse of that value between zero and one is going to be how much do the students influence the teacher.
따라서 이것은 기본적으로 원래 교사 네트워크에서 얼마나 많은 것을 유지하고 있는지에 대한 것이며 0과 1 사이의 값의 역수는 학생이 교사에게 얼마나 많은 영향을 미치는가가 될 것입니다.
Basically how much are they, they're moving average is going to influence the teacher.
기본적으로 이동 평균이 얼마나 되는지가 교사에게 영향을 미칠 것입니다.
So I talked about avoiding collapse earlier with the centering. Basically what this is is the model can experience dimension reduction if we train it too much.
그래서 앞서 센터링으로 붕괴를 피하는 것에 대해 이야기했습니다. 기본적으로 모델을 너무 많이 훈련하면 모델이 차원 축소를 경험할 수 있다는 것입니다.
And then if that happens, it stops being a useful predictor because that means you've lost some sort of variable when you're in your output.
그런 일이 발생하면 유용한 예측 변수가 되지 않습니다. 이는 결과에서 일종의 변수를 잃었다는 의미이기 때문입니다.
And so how do the authors avoid this? Well, these two operations.
그러면 저자는 이를 어떻게 방지합니까? 음, 이 두 가지 작업입니다.
If you use them individually, you'll see they actually can cause the dimension collapse to expedite. So it's basically a balancing act between the two depending on your data set.
개별적으로 사용하면 실제로 치수 축소가 더 빨라질 수 있음을 알 수 있습니다. 따라서 기본적으로 데이터 세트에 따라 둘 사이의 균형을 맞추는 작업입니다.
You use the centering operation to adjust the update rule for the teacher network to be dependent on the mean of each batch.
센터링 작업을 사용하여 Teacher 네트워크의 업데이트 규칙이 각 배치의 평균에 종속되도록 조정합니다.
So basically what this means is each batch and training will have less variance because it's influenced by the mean of all values.
기본적으로 이것이 의미하는 바는 각 배치와 훈련이 모든 값의 평균에 영향을 받기 때문에 분산이 적다는 것입니다.
So you will see it like you'll see the difference between batches is less and so that means each update will have you less likely to be affected by outliers.
따라서 배치 간의 차이가 더 적다는 것을 알 수 있으며, 이는 각 업데이트로 인해 이상값의 영향을 덜 받을 가능성이 있음을 의미합니다.
However, this means you can have the training collapse to some uniform distribution because eventually like that gap will shrink.
그러나 이는 결과적으로 그 격차가 줄어들기 때문에 훈련이 균일한 분포로 붕괴될 수 있음을 의미합니다.
So there's this sharpening, which is this edge enhancement, and it has the opposite effect and accomplished by using a low temperature in the softmax normalization basically making the difference when the probabilities are in the softmax or pronounced because you've added in some sort of value there.
따라서 가장자리 강화인 샤프닝이 있습니다. 이는 반대 효과를 가지며 소프트맥스 정규화에서 낮은 온도를 사용하여 수행됩니다. 기본적으로 확률이 소프트맥스에 있거나 확연한 경우 차이가 발생합니다. 거기에 가치를 두세요.
And if you see the values below here are the centering formulas. So we have some teacher network and then we're just adding some bias term, which is the centering value.
그리고 아래 값이 보이면 센터링 공식이 있습니다. 그래서 우리는 교사 네트워크를 갖고 있고 중심 값인 편향 항을 추가하고 있습니다.
And then the centering value is calculated by some parameter that adjusts based on the batch values, which is that that parameter M is how much the batch influences.
그런 다음 센터링 값은 배치 값을 기반으로 조정되는 일부 매개변수에 의해 계산됩니다. 즉, 해당 매개변수 M은 배치가 영향을 미치는 정도입니다.
So we've talked a lot about how does this, what's the goal of what this model is trying to accomplish, what is it actually using.
그래서 우리는 이것이 어떻게 이루어지는지, 이 모델이 달성하려는 목표는 무엇인지, 실제로 무엇을 사용하는지에 대해 많이 이야기했습니다.
So the architecture for it is it takes the input images, it feeds this into a vision transformer or a ResNet backbone, and then it goes through a projection head, and the projection head is a three layer multi layer perceptron,
따라서 이를 위한 아키텍처는 입력 이미지를 가져와 이를 비전 변환기나 ResNet 백본에 공급한 다음 프로젝션 헤드를 통과하고 프로젝션 헤드는 3층 다층 퍼셉트론입니다.
and then used fed into an L2 norm, which is the function is very similar to Pythagoras, where you're just taking like the square root of each of the components to get the distance.
그런 다음 L2 표준에 공급되는 데 사용됩니다. 이 함수는 피타고라스와 매우 유사합니다. 여기서는 거리를 구하기 위해 각 구성 요소의 제곱근을 사용합니다.
And then you have the fully connected layer, which you use then to make your output.
그런 다음 출력을 만드는 데 사용하는 완전히 연결된 레이어가 있습니다.
So now we'll go into some experiments that they ran. First they compared it on ImageNet, which they wanted to see both in the linear and the k-nears neighbor evaluation.
이제 우리는 그들이 실행한 몇 가지 실험에 대해 살펴보겠습니다. 먼저 그들은 선형 및 k-근접 이웃 평가 모두에서 보고자 했던 ImageNet에서 이를 비교했습니다.
They did it on both ResNet 50 and vision transformer architectures.
그들은 ResNet 50과 비전 변환기 아키텍처 모두에서 이를 수행했습니다.
And you can see that Dino performs the best in all different areas.
그리고 디노가 모든 분야에서 최고의 성과를 내는 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
And also you'll see in when they're comparing the supervised methods, they only did it on the small vision transformers.
또한 감독 방법을 비교할 때 소형 비전 변환기에서만 수행한 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
So on those tests, like you could see a better result given the larger architecture sizes.
따라서 이러한 테스트에서는 아키텍처 크기가 클수록 더 나은 결과를 볼 수 있습니다.
Another thing you can see here too is there's a lot less parameters for Dino when you're comparing with these bigger vision transformers, like even at the largest Dino size with the big eight size patches.
여기서도 볼 수 있는 또 다른 점은 큰 8개 크기 패치가 있는 가장 큰 Dino 크기와 같이 이러한 더 큰 비전 변환기와 비교할 때 Dino에 대한 매개 변수가 훨씬 적다는 것입니다.
And even the 16 size, you'll see 85 parameters and then 312 and 63 images.
크기가 16인 경우에도 85개의 매개변수가 표시되고 그 다음에는 312개와 63개의 이미지가 표시됩니다.
And as you'll see later in the experiments, the smaller patch sizes are better.
그리고 나중에 실험에서 볼 수 있듯이 패치 크기가 작을수록 좋습니다.
The only surprising thing is the k-nears neighbors doesn't actually perform the best on the biggest vision transformer network for some reason. It performs better on the smallest one.
유일한 놀라운 점은 k-near 이웃이 어떤 이유로든 가장 큰 비전 변환기 네트워크에서 실제로 최고의 성능을 발휘하지 못한다는 것입니다. 가장 작은 것에서 더 나은 성능을 발휘합니다.
And so now they also compare the self-supervised learning on four different tasks on ImageNet, being image retrieval, copy detection, video, instant segmentation, and transferring.
이제 그들은 ImageNet의 네 가지 작업(이미지 검색, 복사 감지, 비디오, 즉시 분할 및 전송)에 대한 자기 지도 학습도 비교합니다.
Image retrieval is evaluated on ImageNet and Google Landmarks V2 dataset and how they measure success is through the mean average precision, and it's based on revisited Oxford and Paris as the two locations.
이미지 검색은 ImageNet 및 Google Landmarks V2 데이터 세트에서 평가되며 성공을 측정하는 방법은 평균 평균 정밀도를 통해 이루어지며 옥스퍼드와 파리를 두 위치로 다시 방문한 것을 기반으로 합니다.
The M and H here refer to the severity of the split, so both medium and hard splits, which is just inherent to the dataset.
여기서 M과 H는 분할의 심각도를 나타내므로 중간 분할과 하드 분할이 모두 데이터세트에 내재되어 있습니다.
One thing I find a little weird about this experiment is all the other ones are trained on ImageNet, where the best performing one is trained on a different dataset being this Google Landmarks.
이 실험에서 제가 조금 이상하게 생각하는 점 중 하나는 다른 모든 실험이 ImageNet에서 훈련된다는 것입니다. 여기서 가장 성과가 좋은 실험은 Google 랜드마크라는 다른 데이터세트에서 훈련됩니다.
So, even though with the Google Landmarks, Dino performs the best, I don't necessarily think it's a fair comparison against this R101 was RMAC architecture because they're not being pre-trained on the same data source.
따라서 Google Landmarks를 사용하면 Dino가 가장 좋은 성능을 발휘하지만 동일한 데이터 소스에 대해 사전 학습되지 않았기 때문에 이 R101이 RMAC 아키텍처와 공정한 비교라고 반드시 생각하지는 않습니다.
So, it doesn't necessarily say that Dino is performing better.
따라서 반드시 디노의 성과가 더 좋다는 것은 아닙니다.
Next is the copy detection. Evaluation is on the strong subset of INRA copy data's dataset. The goal is detecting images that have been distorted.
다음은 복사 감지입니다. 평가는 INRA 사본 데이터 데이터세트의 강력한 하위 집합에 대해 이루어집니다. 목표는 왜곡된 이미지를 감지하는 것입니다.
Basically, how I said earlier, we do, we create these views where you can do various effects of them. So, the goal of this is to see has one of those artificial augmentations occurred.
기본적으로 앞서 말했듯이 우리는 다양한 효과를 수행할 수 있는 이러한 뷰를 만듭니다. 따라서 이것의 목표는 인공적인 증강 중 하나가 발생했는지 확인하는 것입니다.
So, they train this on 10K destructor images that are randomly sampled from the dataset described on the slide, and the copy detection uses cosign similarity on the features, and that's how they're ranking the precision there.
따라서 그들은 슬라이드에 설명된 데이터 세트에서 무작위로 샘플링된 10K 소멸자 이미지에 대해 이를 훈련하고 복사 감지는 기능에 대한 동일 부호 유사성을 사용하여 정밀도의 순위를 매깁니다.
20K images were learned to use the features, so what they mean by this is they fine tune the model, or they train the model on the 20,000 images, and then they augmented 10,000 of them, and then they check to see if it could detect those 10,000.
20,000개의 이미지가 특징을 사용하도록 학습되었으므로 이것이 의미하는 바는 모델을 미세 조정하거나 20,000개의 이미지에 대해 모델을 훈련한 다음 그 중 10,000개를 강화한 다음 감지할 수 있는지 확인하는 것입니다. 그 10,000.
You'll see Dino does perform the best at a smaller dimension size, and even at a smaller resolution.
Dino가 더 작은 차원 크기와 더 작은 해상도에서도 최고의 성능을 발휘한다는 것을 알 수 있습니다.
So, that mean, which is a pretty big improvement because the bigger resolution, let me, there's more pixels that the model has to work with, and you can see granularity differences better.
즉, 이는 해상도가 높을수록 모델이 작업해야 하는 픽셀이 더 많아지고 세분성 차이를 더 잘 볼 수 있기 때문에 꽤 큰 개선입니다.
So, next is video instant segmentation.
다음은 비디오 순간 분할입니다.
Basically, we're trying to track features on video files.
기본적으로 우리는 비디오 파일의 특징을 추적하려고 합니다.
Like, imagine we're driving on a road and we want to see the part that's drivable.
예를 들어, 우리가 도로에서 운전하고 있고 운전 가능한 부분을 보고 싶다고 상상해 보세요.
So, this is what the goal of this task would be. It's basically as the video goes along, maintain the different classes, whether it's like the drivable part of a road in a car, through a camera, or.
따라서 이것이 이 작업의 목표가 될 것입니다. 기본적으로 비디오가 진행되는 동안 자동차로 운전할 수 있는 부분이든, 카메라를 통해서든, 다양한 클래스를 유지하는 것입니다.
Separating like an animal in a video as it's flying or something.
날아다니는 동물처럼 영상 속 동물처럼 분리되는 것.
It's trained on ImageNet, and they use two different metrics for this one. There's the mean region similarity, and then there's the contour.
ImageNet에서 훈련되었으며 이에 대해 두 가지 다른 측정항목을 사용합니다. 평균 영역 유사성이 있고 윤곽선이 있습니다.
So, the contour would be kind of like your lines, and then the mean region would be just like the overall area. So, one's like edges and one's the area.
따라서 윤곽선은 선과 비슷하고 평균 영역은 전체 영역과 같습니다. 그래서, 하나는 가장자리와 같고 하나는 면적입니다.
And, as you can see on the right there, they have one where they're both comparing both of them, like the average between the two, and then them independently.
그리고 오른쪽에서 볼 수 있듯이 둘 사이의 평균과 같이 두 가지를 모두 비교한 다음 독립적으로 비교하는 것이 있습니다.
And Dino does the best out of the ImageNet ones. However, there was a different data set that performed significantly better.
그리고 Dino는 ImageNet 제품 중에서 최고의 성능을 발휘합니다. 그러나 훨씬 더 나은 성능을 보이는 다른 데이터 세트가 있었습니다.
So, maybe they should have tried this on that data set as well, but on ImageNet, Dino does perform the best.
따라서 해당 데이터 세트에서도 이 작업을 시도했어야 했지만 ImageNet에서는 Dino가 가장 좋은 성능을 발휘했습니다.
So, here's some examples of this video.
자, 여기 이 비디오의 몇 가지 예가 있습니다.
Instant segmentation, if you want to see like more qualitative results, you can see like the red area is the segmented object.
즉각적인 세분화, 보다 질적인 결과를 보고 싶다면 빨간색 영역이 분할된 개체인 것처럼 볼 수 있습니다.
And then in the supervised approach, you can see more little red dots, especially in the group of ducks in the image where it's not actually the ducks that it's trying to segment.
그런 다음 감독된 접근 방식에서는 작은 빨간색 점을 더 많이 볼 수 있습니다. 특히 분할하려는 오리가 아닌 이미지의 오리 그룹에서 특히 그렇습니다.
And basically what the segmentation is, is it's a mask obtained. So, we're trying to like, if imagine a matrix, highlight the points where the objects is in that particular class.
기본적으로 분할은 마스크를 얻는 것입니다. 그래서 우리는 행렬을 상상해 보면 객체가 특정 클래스에 있는 지점을 강조하려고 노력하고 있습니다.
And the threshold for this is 60% and it's based upon the self-attention maps in the transformer.
이에 대한 임계값은 60%이며 이는 변환기의 셀프 어텐션 맵을 기반으로 합니다.
And the comparison similarity is using the, sorry, the comparison is using the jacquard similarity from images on Pascal VOC12 data set.
그리고 비교 유사성은 죄송합니다. 비교는 Pascal VOC12 데이터 세트의 이미지에서 자카드 유사성을 사용하고 있습니다.
And Dino performed significantly better than the compared against models.
그리고 Dino는 모델과 비교했을 때 훨씬 더 나은 성능을 보였습니다.
Where the compared against models were almost the same as random.
모델과 비교한 결과는 무작위와 거의 동일했습니다.
The next task is transfer learning. So Dino versus the supervised approach when evaluating transfer learning, you know, it performs almost every data set for both networks.
다음 작업은 전이 학습입니다. 따라서 전이 학습을 평가할 때 Dino와 감독 방식은 두 네트워크 모두에 대해 거의 모든 데이터 세트를 수행합니다.
The difference is very small. So, like, most of these are fairly marginal improvements other than like, maybe the ImageNet one, but it's still an improvement nonetheless.
그 차이는 매우 작습니다. 따라서 이들 중 대부분은 ImageNet과 같은 것 외에는 상당히 미미한 개선이지만 그럼에도 불구하고 여전히 개선된 것입니다.
So the abolition study of Dino is basically we're trying to see what parts of the model in Dino are actually more beneficial than others.
따라서 Dino의 폐지 연구는 기본적으로 Dino 모델의 어떤 부분이 실제로 다른 부분보다 더 유익한지 확인하려고 노력하는 것입니다.
We first, we noticed that small patch sizes show better performance. However, the cost is significantly slower. So the 16 by 16 patches will perform worse than the 8 by 8s.
먼저, 작은 패치 크기가 더 나은 성능을 보인다는 점을 확인했습니다. 그러나 비용은 상당히 느립니다. 따라서 16 x 16 패치는 8 x 8 패치보다 성능이 더 나쁩니다.
Given that, but obviously it'll be slower because if there are only 8 by 8 patches, that means there's more tokens for the model to learn.
하지만 8 x 8 패치만 있으면 모델이 학습할 토큰이 더 많아지기 때문에 분명히 속도가 느려질 것입니다.
And you can see that by the throughput versus the performance increase.
그리고 처리량 대비 성능 증가를 통해 이를 확인할 수 있습니다.
Where the increase benefit is more pronounced is on the DIT transformer going from 16 to 8 has multiple percentage points increase where on vision transformers.
증가 이점이 더 두드러지는 곳은 DIT 변환기에서 16에서 8로 가는 것인데 비전 변환기에서는 여러 퍼센트 포인트 증가합니다.
It was it's closer to one.
1번에 더 가까웠어요.
Next, it's highlighting on basically what features in Dino affect the performance in the various compared to the default settings.
다음으로, 기본적으로 Dino의 어떤 기능이 기본 설정과 비교하여 다양한 성능에 영향을 미치는지 강조합니다.
So, for instance, the sync horn knob has minimal effect. If we include that setting.
예를 들어 싱크 혼 노브의 효과는 최소화됩니다. 해당 설정을 포함한다면.
Compared to the base model, there is a 0.6% difference that can use neighbors and a 0.1% difference on the linear.
기본 모델과 비교하면 이웃을 사용할 수 있는 경우는 0.6%, 선형에서는 0.1%의 차이가 있습니다.
However, if we don't have the momentum encoder, the accuracy goes to zero. So obviously this thing's crucial.
그러나 운동량 인코더가 없으면 정확도는 0이 됩니다. 그래서 분명히 이것이 중요합니다.
Next, the multi crop is about a 5% or we have 4 to 5% depending on if you're looking can years neighbor linear decrease on each of them respectively.
다음으로, 다작물은 약 5%이거나 각각의 연도 이웃 선형 감소를 보고 있는지 여부에 따라 4~5%입니다.
And similarly, if you go to mean squared error instead of cross entropy, you see a significant decrease.
마찬가지로 교차 엔트로피 대신 평균 제곱 오차로 이동하면 상당한 감소를 볼 수 있습니다.
Next, we're going to talk about mask auto encoders are scalable vision learners.
다음으로 마스크 자동 인코더가 확장 가능한 비전 학습자에 대해 이야기하겠습니다.
So this paper introduces an asymmetric encoder decoder architecture, which what I mean by this is the encoder uses a subset of the data set and decoder uses encoded data plus learned component to represent the rest of input image.
따라서 이 문서에서는 비대칭 인코더 디코더 아키텍처를 소개합니다. 즉, 인코더는 데이터 세트의 하위 집합을 사용하고 디코더는 인코딩된 데이터와 학습된 구성 요소를 사용하여 나머지 입력 이미지를 표현한다는 의미입니다.
And it shows masking a high proportion of the input image to be meaningful subsurface.
그리고 의미 있는 지하 표면이 되기 위해 입력 이미지의 높은 비율을 마스킹하는 것을 보여줍니다.
My mean by this is learning like mask through a large part of the image is just a good predictor when it comes to vision learning and using mask auto encoders.
내 말은 이미지의 큰 부분을 통해 마스크처럼 학습하는 것은 비전 학습 및 마스크 자동 인코더 사용과 관련하여 좋은 예측 변수일 뿐이라는 것입니다.
The training speeds increase from 2.8 to 4.1 times respect, depending on the input parameters in the model.
훈련 속도는 모델의 입력 매개변수에 따라 2.8배에서 4.1배로 증가합니다.
So first we'll talk about what is a mask. Well, I kind of talked about a little bit earlier, but it's a matrix use to determine which parts of the input image to use.
그럼 먼저 마스크가 무엇인지부터 알아보겠습니다. 글쎄요, 제가 좀 더 일찍 얘기한 적이 있지만, 사용할 입력 이미지의 어떤 부분을 결정하는 데는 매트릭스를 사용하는 것입니다.
So, if on the left hand side we had this cheetah, all the parts that are colored are the parts of the image we want to use that in the mask, and then everything else is represented by zeros in the gray section.
따라서 왼쪽에 이 치타가 있는 경우 색칠된 모든 부분은 마스크에서 사용하려는 이미지 부분이고 나머지 모든 부분은 회색 섹션에서 0으로 표시됩니다.
And then what the goal of the mask is to do is it's to try and rebuild that image. So that's the middle it's like that's the rebuild what the model would predict, given the initial input image on the right.
그리고 마스크의 목적은 그 이미지를 재구성하는 것입니다. 이것이 중간입니다. 오른쪽의 초기 입력 이미지가 주어지면 모델이 예측하는 재구성과 같습니다.
So if we know we know what a mask is. Well, what kind of strategies are important here. Like, as you can see here, there's random there's block, there's grid, which ones perform better.
그래서 우리가 알면 마스크가 무엇인지 알 수 있습니다. 자, 여기서는 어떤 전략이 중요할까요? 여기에서 볼 수 있듯이 무작위로 블록이 있고 그리드가 있는데 어느 것이 더 나은 성능을 발휘하는지 알 수 있습니다.
What about different sizes like what if I only mask 25% of the image 50, 75% do these different ratios of performance.
이미지의 25%만 마스크하면 50, 75%가 서로 다른 성능 비율을 수행하는 등 다양한 크기는 어떻습니까?
And, but you can see here, when you look at the random that it performs the best out of them, because like if you look at the grid, although the parts where the grid is didn't mask things.
그리고 여기에서 볼 수 있듯이 무작위를 볼 때 그 중 가장 좋은 성능을 발휘한다는 것을 알 수 있습니다. 왜냐하면 그리드를 보는 것처럼 그리드가 있는 부분이 사물을 가리지는 않았지만요.
It's very clear. You have this grid like block pattern all over where there's a clear distinction on the mask didn't perform too well.
매우 명확합니다. 마스크에 명확한 구분이 있는 블록 패턴과 같은 그리드가 있어 제대로 작동하지 않았습니다.
And then the block you see a similar like this huge parts of blurring where it just didn't have any information anywhere nearby. So it just like it can't predict that pixel very well where the random.
그리고 블록에는 근처 어디에도 정보가 전혀 없는 흐릿한 부분과 유사한 유사한 부분이 표시됩니다. 따라서 무작위인 경우 해당 픽셀을 잘 예측할 수 없는 것과 같습니다.
Although certain aspects may be slightly worse overall it's a better image.
특정 측면은 전체적으로 약간 더 나쁠 수 있지만 이미지는 더 좋습니다.
So now, what is a mask auto encoder. Well,
그럼 이제 마스크 자동 인코더란 무엇일까요? 잘,
we're going to start the simple approach like as we did on the last paper and we'll slowly expand upon and making it more complex on how we describe it.
우리는 지난 논문에서 했던 것처럼 간단한 접근 방식을 시작할 것이고, 그것을 설명하는 방법을 천천히 확장하여 더욱 복잡하게 만들 것입니다.
So first, we're going to take the input image and we're going to ignore a portion of the input, either masking and then we feed into the encoder.
먼저 입력 이미지를 가져와 입력의 일부를 무시하거나 마스킹한 다음 인코더에 입력합니다.
That remaining data, then we add some additional features. So this is the positional data. So this is the features we're trying to learn to.
남은 데이터에 몇 가지 추가 기능을 추가합니다. 이것이 위치 데이터입니다. 이것이 우리가 배우려고 하는 기능입니다.
So when the decoder can recreate the image.
따라서 디코더가 이미지를 다시 생성할 수 있을 때입니다.
And then once we decode the image we use that data to reconstruct.
그런 다음 이미지를 디코딩하면 해당 데이터를 사용하여 재구성합니다.
We use the decoded data to reconstruct the image.
우리는 디코딩된 데이터를 사용하여 이미지를 재구성합니다.
So on this figure on the right we have some mass data. We only include this mass data. These blue parts represent the mist where the mask was.
오른쪽 그림에는 대량 데이터가 있습니다. 우리는 이 대량 데이터만 포함합니다. 이 파란색 부분은 마스크가 있던 부분의 안개를 나타냅니다.
Or like the positional data for these input images and then everything else is the gray squares or what we're trying to learn in the decoder.
또는 이러한 입력 이미지에 대한 위치 데이터와 같은 경우 다른 모든 것은 회색 사각형이거나 디코더에서 학습하려는 것입니다.
And then we reconstruct the image through that decoded data.
그런 다음 디코딩된 데이터를 통해 이미지를 재구성합니다.
So more formally, we approach this as we define the input into a series of patches. So those are the grids. We samples a set of those patches and mask the rest.
좀 더 공식적으로는 입력을 일련의 패치로 정의하면서 이에 접근합니다. 이것이 바로 그리드입니다. 우리는 해당 패치 세트를 샘플링하고 나머지는 마스크합니다.
So each of those patches where the grids on the previous square.
따라서 각 패치는 이전 사각형에 그리드가 있습니다.
The mask encoder, it uses a vision transformer to take the unmasked patches as inputs.
마스크 인코더는 비전 변환기를 사용하여 마스크되지 않은 패치를 입력으로 사용합니다.
We embed the unmasked patches. And then we process this using a series of transformer blocks, which I'll explain more about later.
마스크되지 않은 패치를 삽입합니다. 그런 다음 일련의 변환기 블록을 사용하여 이를 처리합니다. 이에 대해서는 나중에 자세히 설명하겠습니다.
The decoder is both these encoded visible patches and a set of mask tokens. These mass tokens are a shared learn feature vector representing each of the missing patches.
디코더는 인코딩된 가시 패치이자 마스크 토큰 세트입니다. 이러한 대량 토큰은 누락된 각 패치를 나타내는 공유 학습 기능 벡터입니다.
The reconstruction target here is the decoder's output that is reshaped to form the reconstructed image. And we've entered the loss of this of the mean squared error between the predicted and the original image.
여기서 재구성 대상은 재구성된 이미지를 형성하기 위해 재구성되는 디코더의 출력입니다. 그리고 우리는 예측된 이미지와 원본 이미지 사이의 평균 제곱 오차에 대한 손실을 입력했습니다.
So the abolition study is, once again, what is important in the model.
따라서 폐지 연구는 다시 한번 모델에서 중요한 것입니다.
So there's two different things that they're comparing it. It's a fine tuned and a linear probed.
그래서 그들이 비교하는 두 가지 다른 것이 있습니다. 미세 조정 및 선형 프로브입니다.
Part of the encoder. So.
인코더의 일부입니다. 그래서.
And the first part is saying like, okay, how many blocks should we do.
첫 번째 부분은 '얼마나 많은 블록을 해야 할까요?'라고 말하는 것입니다.
And you can see there's a middle ground like you don't want to go too far.
그리고 너무 멀리 가고 싶지 않은 중간 지점이 있다는 것을 알 수 있습니다.
We're both models performed both fine tuning and linear perform best at eight.
우리는 두 모델 모두 미세 조정과 선형을 모두 수행하여 8에서 가장 좋은 성능을 발휘했습니다.
And then the width.
그리고 너비.
It's just how wise the feature vector.
그것은 특징 벡터가 얼마나 현명한가입니다.
I'm guessing this also has to do more with the input image size.
나는 이것이 또한 입력 이미지 크기와 더 많은 관련이 있다고 생각합니다.
It performs better at the 512.
512에서 더 나은 성능을 발휘합니다.
And then is the
그리고 다음은
Is encoding with mass tokens or without better.
대량 토큰을 사용하거나 더 나은 인코딩을 사용하지 않고 인코딩합니다.
And you can see.
그리고 당신은 볼 수 있습니다.
And so the flocks is how much like how much complexity it adds.
그래서 무리는 그것이 얼마나 많은 복잡성을 추가하는지와 비슷합니다.
If we don't include the mass token. So basically we only include.
대량 토큰을 포함하지 않는 경우. 그래서 기본적으로 우리는 단지 포함합니다.
The parts that are meaningful inputs from the image.
이미지에서 의미 있는 입력이 되는 부분입니다.
See a significant increase in the linear probing performance and a slight increase in the fine tuning.
선형 프로빙 성능이 크게 향상되고 미세 조정이 약간 증가한 것을 확인하세요.
But it's 3.3 times less of operations that have to be processed.
하지만 처리해야 하는 작업은 3.3배 적습니다.
So that's a significant increase in speed.
그래서 속도가 크게 향상되었습니다.
Where the reconstruction target.
재건축 대상이 되는 곳.
You see pixel with normalization performance better than PCA or.
PCA 또는 정규화 성능이 더 나은 픽셀을 볼 수 있습니다.
The token approach.
토큰 접근 방식.
And date augmentation.
그리고 날짜 확대.
The cropped in random size performs better than cropped big size or.
무작위 크기로 자른 것이 큰 크기로 자른 것보다 성능이 더 좋습니다.
Yeah.
응.
And mass sampling. So this is the difference with the ratios and.
그리고 대량 샘플링. 이것이 비율과의 차이점입니다.
What kind of strategy and here random with 75% mask performs the best.
어떤 종류의 전략과 여기에서 75% 마스크를 사용하는 무작위가 가장 효과적입니다.
Now here's the comparison to the models.
이제 모델과의 비교를 살펴보겠습니다.
So they can you can see here compares better against Dino.
여기에서 볼 수 있듯이 Dino와 비교하면 더 좋습니다.
And even also this be it when it's also fine tuned on another data set as well, not just the in the image net 1k.
또한 이미지 네트 1k뿐만 아니라 다른 데이터 세트에서도 미세 조정되는 경우에도 마찬가지입니다.
And performs better at all sizes.
그리고 모든 규모에서 더 나은 성능을 발휘합니다.
And then yeah, so the another key thing you'll see here is.
그리고 네, 여기서 보게 될 또 다른 핵심 사항은 다음과 같습니다.
The big big 16 the large 16 and huge 16.
큰 것 16, 큰 것 16, 거대한 것 16.
Are the models and so they just represent the size of the model and also the patch size.
모델이므로 모델의 크기와 패치 크기를 나타냅니다.
And then the their images are all 224 by 224 except for the vision transformer huge is 448.
그리고 이미지는 모두 224 x 224입니다. 단, 거대한 비전 트랜스포머의 크기는 448입니다.
Or the one that has the subscript of that.
아니면 그 아래첨자가 있는 것.
Next, so in this is another key experiment. It's basically.
다음은 또 다른 주요 실험입니다. 기본적으로입니다.
Rather than just linear probing or full fine tuning.
단순한 선형 프로빙이나 전체 미세 조정이 아닙니다.
They want to try and do a mini or a mid ground between the two.
그들은 둘 사이에 미니 또는 미드 그라운드를 시도하고 싶어합니다.
Which is this like to say, can we.
이것은 우리가 말할 수 있는 것과 같습니다.
Train a portion of the model like that being some of the transformer blocks.
일부 변환기 블록과 같은 모델의 일부를 훈련합니다.
And improve the results rather than training all of them.
그리고 모두 훈련하기보다는 결과를 개선하세요.
Where and then you want to do this be the idea behind this is because linear probing does not capture.
선형 프로빙이 캡처하지 않기 때문에 이 작업을 수행하려는 경우 이 아이디어가 필요합니다.
Nonlinear features because it's a linear method, but it's very good at linear features.
선형 방법이기 때문에 비선형 특성이지만 선형 특성에는 매우 좋습니다.
Where the fine tuning and the deep learning approach can capture these nonlinear features.
미세 조정과 딥 러닝 접근 방식을 통해 이러한 비선형 특징을 포착할 수 있습니다.
So.
그래서.
If we know our data set does have these nonlinear features, we can fine tune some of the transformer blocks.
데이터 세트에 이러한 비선형 특징이 있다는 것을 알고 있다면 일부 변환기 블록을 미세 조정할 수 있습니다.
And the order of them is specific.
그리고 그 순서는 구체적입니다.
They did the authors in this paper did train specific transformer blocks in an order.
이 문서의 저자는 특정 변압기 블록을 순서대로 훈련했습니다.
Rather than just starting from 1st and because not all of them have the same benefit.
처음부터 시작하는 것이 아니라 모두가 동일한 이점을 갖지 않기 때문입니다.
But you can see.
그러나 당신은 볼 수 있습니다.
That it does make a meaningful difference when we're training.
우리가 훈련할 때 의미 있는 차이를 만든다는 것입니다.
4 to 6, you can see a significant improvement.
4~6에서는 상당한 개선을 볼 수 있습니다.
As opposed to 0 and going from 18 to 24, you don't really see much improvement, even from 12.
0과 반대로 18에서 24로 가더라도 12에서조차 큰 개선이 보이지 않습니다.
So that can also like speed up your model significantly if you only partially fine tune it.
따라서 부분적으로만 미세 조정하면 모델 속도가 크게 향상될 수도 있습니다.
Next is the transfer learning. It's a common task in any machine learning.
다음은 전이학습이다. 이는 모든 머신러닝에서 일반적인 작업입니다.
If we train something once can we.
우리가 무언가를 한 번 훈련하면 할 수 있습니다.
Transfer to a different task that learned component.
구성 요소를 학습한 다른 작업으로 전환합니다.
So the mascot on quarter performs better than all of the other papers.
따라서 분기의 마스코트는 다른 모든 논문보다 더 나은 성능을 발휘합니다.
And on all the other data sets unsurprisingly the biggest model performs better.
그리고 다른 모든 데이터 세트에서는 당연히 가장 큰 모델이 더 나은 성능을 발휘합니다.
Here, they also compare against using pixels or tokens as the reconstruction target and the difference between them is represented at the bottom through this delta.
여기서도 픽셀이나 토큰을 재구성 대상으로 사용하는 것과 비교하며 이들 간의 차이는 이 델타를 통해 하단에 표시됩니다.
You can see there really isn't much of a difference between them.
실제로 보면 둘 사이에 큰 차이가 없다는 것을 알 수 있습니다.
Whether you're using the token or the normalized pixel.
토큰을 사용하는지, 정규화된 픽셀을 사용하는지 여부.
So the next paper is meta former is actually what you need for vision that proposes a generalized architecture for transformers that don't use attention demonstrates that even a simple token mixer such as pooling can produce competitive results and computer vision tasks.
따라서 다음 논문은 주의를 사용하지 않는 변환기에 대한 일반화된 아키텍처를 제안하는 비전에 실제로 필요한 메타포머입니다. 이는 풀링과 같은 간단한 토큰 혼합기도 경쟁력 있는 결과와 컴퓨터 비전 작업을 생성할 수 있음을 보여줍니다.
Meta former so we're going to talk about just in a brief idea what the metaphor is and it's model, and then we'll go into it more in depth.
메타 포머이므로 은유가 무엇인지, 모델인지 간략하게 설명하고 좀 더 깊이 들어가 보겠습니다.
So metaphor is an abstracted architecture. It's to drive from transformers.
따라서 은유는 추상화된 아키텍처입니다. 변압기에서 운전하는 것입니다.
And the idea here is we remove attention from transformers and where intent intention is the token mixer. Let's say metaphor just uses some generalized token mixer and then your specific implementation can use whatever you want.
그리고 여기서의 아이디어는 변환기로부터 주의를 제거하고 의도 의도가 토큰 믹서인 곳입니다. 비유가 일반화된 토큰 믹서를 사용하고 특정 구현에서 원하는 것을 사용할 수 있다고 가정해 보겠습니다.
And the authors show that.
그리고 저자는 그것을 보여줍니다.
Meta former that so the like ordering of how you have these blocks is more important by using this architecture called pool former where instead of the more complicated attention task very or.
더 복잡한 주의 작업 대신 풀 포머라고 불리는 이 아키텍처를 사용하면 이러한 블록을 갖는 방법과 같은 순서를 지정하는 메타 포머가 더 중요합니다.
Yeah, they're using this pooling.
네, 그들은 이 풀링을 사용하고 있습니다.
Block to connect.
연결을 차단합니다.
Instead, and.
대신, 그리고.
So, first we'll talk about what is pool former.
그럼 먼저 풀 포머(Poll Former)가 무엇인지부터 이야기해보겠습니다.
Sorry, we'll go back here. We'll explain what these things are. So to refresh you.
죄송합니다. 여기로 다시 돌아가겠습니다. 이것들이 무엇인지 설명드리겠습니다. 그래서 당신을 상쾌하게합니다.
On these what these transformer blocks are is you have some input embedding. And then you feed that in with the normalization through the token mixer. So the token mixer.
이러한 변환기 블록은 일부 입력 임베딩을 가지고 있다는 것입니다. 그런 다음 토큰 믹서를 통해 정규화를 적용합니다. 그래서 토큰 믹서.
Affects what the input embedding does and like how much influence of the model. It goes through another normalization and then also through the multi layer perceptron and increase the input.
입력 임베딩의 기능과 모델의 영향 정도에 영향을 미칩니다. 또 다른 정규화를 거친 다음 다층 퍼셉트론을 거쳐 입력을 증가시킵니다.
So, this is what a pool former.
이것이 바로 풀 전의 모습입니다.
Block looks like.
블록의 모습입니다.
Like, first we'll talk about the pool former block. It's that's normalization, the pooling, and then the normalization, the channel.
먼저 풀 이전 블록에 대해 이야기하겠습니다. 그것은 정규화, 풀링, 그리고 정규화, 즉 채널입니다.
So, first we have the input image. Let's say is this cat.
먼저 입력 이미지가 있습니다. 이 고양이가 있다고 가정 해 봅시다.
The three is just the different channels, red, green, blue, with the image.
세 개는 이미지의 빨간색, 녹색, 파란색이라는 서로 다른 채널일 뿐입니다.
We embed the image.
이미지를 삽입합니다.
And then the first stage is we down sample it by four.
그리고 첫 번째 단계에서는 4개씩 다운샘플링합니다.
This stage uses a ratio of a sixth of a sixth of the total number of blocks in the architecture. So, in these transformer architectures, we can have increasingly large number of blocks.
이 단계에서는 아키텍처의 전체 블록 수의 6분의 1의 비율을 사용합니다. 따라서 이러한 변환기 아키텍처에서는 점점 더 많은 수의 블록을 가질 수 있습니다.
And this is basically just saying the ratio of it is one sixth of that number.
그리고 이것은 기본적으로 그 비율이 그 숫자의 6분의 1이라고 말하는 것입니다.
Then the second, then we go through another patch embedding. We downsize it in half again using also a sixth of the pool former blocks.
그런 다음 두 번째로 또 다른 패치 임베딩을 진행합니다. 풀 이전 블록의 6분의 1을 사용하여 다시 절반으로 줄였습니다.
And then we downsize it again after embedding it and half. And this time we use half of the total number of blocks and then we embed and then do a sixth.
그런 다음 절반을 삽입한 후 다시 크기를 줄입니다. 그리고 이번에는 전체 블록 수의 절반을 사용한 다음 삽입하고 여섯 번째 블록을 수행합니다.
And then we create our output.
그런 다음 출력을 생성합니다.
But yeah, the key thing to note here is the ratio of the pool former blocks. So, let's say we had our first architecture, the smallest size was six.
하지만 네, 여기서 주목해야 할 핵심 사항은 풀 이전 블록의 비율입니다. 첫 번째 아키텍처가 있다고 가정해 보겠습니다. 가장 작은 크기는 6개였습니다.
Stage one, two and four would each have one one block and then stage three would have three blocks.
1단계, 2단계, 4단계에는 각각 하나의 블록이 있고 3단계에는 3개의 블록이 있습니다.
So, the results. This was on image classification, object detection, and segmentation, and say static segmentation for the three tasks.
결과는 다음과 같습니다. 이는 이미지 분류, 객체 감지 및 분할에 관한 것이며 세 가지 작업에 대한 정적 분할을 말합니다.
Here, there's just a bunch of different architectures and they represent different types of things that they're comparing against. So, for instance, pool formers are proposed.
여기에는 다양한 아키텍처가 있으며 비교 대상이 되는 다양한 유형을 나타냅니다. 예를 들어, 풀 포머(pool form)가 제안됩니다.
Any multi layer perceptron one, which is going to be is done through for spatial MLP. So that's the site.
모든 다층 퍼셉트론은 공간 MLP를 통해 수행됩니다. 그래서 그 사이트입니다.
The right side triangle, and then the upwards facing one are your attention based token mixers, and then the downwards one is a resonant so they're comparing against different types of
오른쪽 삼각형과 위쪽을 향한 삼각형은 주의 기반 토큰 믹서이고 아래쪽 삼각형은 공명이므로 다양한 유형의 토큰과 비교됩니다.
token mixers and the pooling performs better than all of them, even though it's a very simple operation.
토큰 믹서와 풀링은 매우 간단한 작업임에도 불구하고 그 모든 것보다 더 나은 성능을 발휘합니다.
And also this max is number of like actual
또한 이 최대값은 실제와 같은 수입니다.
actual computing operations it has to do.
실제 컴퓨팅 작업을 수행해야 합니다.
And it also performs better accuracy at lower number for across all comparisons, where even smaller model sizes is the left hand.
또한 더 작은 모델 크기가 왼손인 경우 모든 비교에서 더 낮은 숫자에서 더 나은 정확도를 수행합니다.
Object detection and instant segmentation.
객체 감지 및 즉각적인 분할.
So this is just comparing against different sized bounding boxes and
따라서 이것은 단지 다른 크기의 경계 상자와 비교하는 것입니다.
different masking ratios. So it's the small, medium, large objects, and then the bounding boxes, the percentage threshold pool former performs better than the resnet comparison.
마스킹 비율이 다릅니다. 따라서 소형, 중형, 대형 개체와 경계 상자의 비율 임계값 풀 이전이 resnet 비교보다 더 나은 성능을 발휘합니다.
The mask or it's on red in that that it's trained on.
마스크 또는 훈련을 받았다는 점에서 빨간색입니다.
And it also has less parameters, other than at the small size,
그리고 작은 크기를 제외하면 매개변수도 적습니다.
which is consistent with the other experiments.
이는 다른 실험과 일치합니다.
The segmented segmentation.
분할된 세분화입니다.
It's done on 20 K images for training and 2 K images for validation.
훈련용으로 20K 이미지를 사용하고 검증용으로 2K 이미지를 사용했습니다.
And it's compared against both resonant and tension based architectures, and it performs better than all of them, and out a smaller parameter size.
공진 기반 아키텍처와 장력 기반 아키텍처를 모두 비교한 결과, 모든 아키텍처보다 성능이 뛰어나고 매개변수 크기가 더 작습니다.
And the target metric here is the mean intersection over union.
여기서 목표 측정항목은 합집합에 대한 평균 교차점입니다.
So the evaluation study is so this is saying like okay.
그래서 평가 연구는 그래서 이것이 괜찮다고 말하는 것입니다.
The results of this generalized.
이에 대한 결과가 일반화되었습니다.
They are better because we're talking about metaphormers. We're trying to see, can we generalize transformers.
우리는 은유에 대해 이야기하고 있기 때문에 더 좋습니다. 우리는 변환기를 일반화할 수 있는지 알아보려고 합니다.
And show that it isn't just attention.
그리고 그것이 단순한 관심이 아니라는 것을 보여주세요.
So by adjusting the pooling size.
따라서 풀링 크기를 조정하면 됩니다.
You can see there's slight differences in performance, but not majorly, but going to a depth wise convolution.
성능에 약간의 차이가 있음을 알 수 있지만 크게는 아니지만 깊이 있는 컨볼루션으로 이동합니다.
You can see a larger increase in performance similar requirements in computation.
계산 시 성능 요구 사항과 유사하게 더 큰 증가를 확인할 수 있습니다.
And then another thing you see is going for normalization. If you have no normalization you perform significantly worse difference between batch and layer is very small, but this modified layer normalization is the best.
그리고 또 다른 것은 정규화를 향한 것입니다. 정규화가 없으면 배치와 레이어 간의 차이가 훨씬 더 심해집니다. 그러나 이 수정된 레이어 정규화가 가장 좋습니다.
So if you have no normalization you perform significantly worse difference between a relu and see Lou and these other activation layers, you'll see slight differences.
따라서 정규화가 없으면 relu 사이에 훨씬 더 나쁜 차이를 수행하고 Lou와 이러한 다른 활성화 레이어를 보면 약간의 차이가 있음을 알 수 있습니다.
And other components like this, if you remove the residual residual connection and the multi layer perceptron head.
그리고 이와 같은 다른 구성 요소는 잔여 잔여 연결과 다층 퍼셉트론 헤드를 제거하면 됩니다.
The accuracy just pretty much goes to zero.
정확도는 거의 0에 가깝습니다.
So here this is also just showing that even though they used pooling for this architecture, the architecture does perform better with attention. So here they've switched stages three and four.
따라서 이는 이 아키텍처에 풀링을 사용했음에도 불구하고 아키텍처가 주의를 기울일 때 더 나은 성능을 발휘한다는 것을 보여줍니다. 그래서 여기에서는 3단계와 4단계를 전환했습니다.
So that's two thirds of the total transformer blocks with attention token mixers.
이는 주의 토큰 믹서가 포함된 전체 변압기 블록의 2/3에 해당합니다.
You can see a multiple percentage increase in performance with only a 25% increase a little bit over than that and computation that needs to be done, and about a third increase in parameters.
수행해야 하는 계산과 매개변수의 약 3분의 1 증가보다 약간만 25%만 증가하면 성능이 몇 퍼센트 증가하는 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
So that is a key point that even though this paper focuses on the generalization is not saying that attention doesn't improve the model is just saying that it's not really the key thing you want to focus on when making your architecture.
따라서 이 문서가 일반화에 중점을 두더라도 주의가 모델을 개선하지 않는다고 말하는 것이 아니라 아키텍처를 만들 때 실제로 집중하고 싶은 핵심 사항이 아니라고 말하는 것이 핵심입니다.
Next it's with former efficient additive attention for transformer based real time mobile vision applications. So in here it's the introduction of efficient additive attention.
다음은 변압기 기반 실시간 모바일 비전 애플리케이션을 위한 이전의 효율적인 추가 주의입니다. 그래서 여기에는 효율적인 덧셈 주의가 도입되었습니다.
It reduces the expensive matrix location operations with an additive approach where the tension and all the other ones was, yeah, it's a matrix multiplication. So when we're dealing with these large inputs and just lots of processing because we run many iterations that
장력과 다른 모든 것들이 행렬 곱셈인 부가적 접근 방식을 사용하여 비용이 많이 드는 행렬 위치 작업을 줄입니다. 따라서 우리가 이러한 큰 입력과 많은 처리량을 처리할 때 우리는 많은 반복을 실행하기 때문에
are expensive operation that is multiple matrix multiplication adds up over time. So the key point here, and that's where most of the time what we spent on is talking about how this reduction occurs.
시간이 지남에 따라 다중 행렬 곱셈이 추가되는 비용이 많이 드는 작업입니다. 여기서 핵심은 우리가 소비한 대부분의 시간이 이러한 감소가 어떻게 발생하는지에 대해 이야기하는 것입니다.
Yeah, so as we remind ourselves, attention squares are computed by taking the soft max of two matrices q and k with the dimensions.
예, 우리가 상기한 바와 같이 주의 제곱은 차원과 함께 두 행렬 q와 k의 소프트 최대값을 취하여 계산됩니다.
And so the time complexity that is n squared times the dimension size. But if we transpose q, instead of K, then that complexity goes to d squared, like n times d squared, instead of n squared times d.
그리고 시간 복잡도는 차원 크기의 n 제곱배입니다. 그러나 K 대신 q를 전치하면 그 복잡성은 n 제곱 곱하기 d 대신 n 곱하기 d 제곱과 같이 d 제곱으로 이동합니다.
And Q, K and V are the three different matrices used in transformers. It's the keys, the values and the query.
Q, K, V는 변압기에 사용되는 세 가지 서로 다른 행렬입니다. 키, 값 및 쿼리입니다.
So the first way that attention has been improved is through this separable self attention. So given K queries, key or K keys and V values being code them element wise.
따라서 주의력이 향상되는 첫 번째 방법은 분리 가능한 자기 주의력을 이용하는 것입니다. 따라서 K 쿼리가 주어지면 키 또는 K 키와 V 값이 요소별로 코딩됩니다.
So rather than encoding them matrix wise if we're encoding the elements because this thing scales nonlinearly it'll perform faster.
따라서 요소를 인코딩하는 경우 비선형적으로 확장되기 때문에 행렬 방식으로 인코딩하는 것보다 더 빠르게 수행됩니다.
So first to do this we project the query matrix q into n by one vector q apply a soft max to create context scores.
먼저 이를 수행하기 위해 쿼리 행렬 q를 하나의 벡터 q로 n에 투영하고 소프트 최대값을 적용하여 컨텍스트 점수를 생성합니다.
We multiply context scores by the matrix K and pool to create a context vector s element wise multiplication between S and V return the attention scores.
컨텍스트 점수에 행렬 K를 곱하고 풀을 사용하여 컨텍스트 벡터 S와 V 간의 요소별 곱셈을 생성하여 어텐션 점수를 반환합니다.
So instead of just multiplying these two matrix, we have a summation of a bunch of smaller multiplications.
따라서 이 두 행렬을 단순히 곱하는 대신 여러 개의 작은 곱셈의 합을 얻습니다.
Next is efficient additive attention as we saw traditionally attention depends on three components. What if we remove this key value interaction during the encoding.
다음은 전통적으로 주의가 세 가지 구성 요소에 따라 달라지는 것을 보았듯이 효율적인 추가 주의입니다. 인코딩 중에 이 키 값 상호 작용을 제거하면 어떻게 될까요?
That's what an efficient additive attention is. So the model rather retains that interaction through linear production layer.
이것이 바로 효율적인 덧셈 주의입니다. 따라서 모델은 오히려 선형 생산 계층을 통해 해당 상호 작용을 유지합니다.
So now the modeling depends on two matrices q and K. So how does this do it.
이제 모델링은 두 개의 행렬 q와 K에 의존합니다. 그러면 이것이 어떻게 수행됩니까?
It creates this global attention query vector. So we're going to let alpha represent this query vector where the weights like W subscript a is a learnable parameter for the attention weights.
이 글로벌 어텐션 쿼리 벡터를 생성합니다. 따라서 우리는 알파가 W 첨자 a와 같은 가중치가 어텐션 가중치에 대한 학습 가능한 매개변수인 이 쿼리 벡터를 나타내도록 할 것입니다.
And we calculate this query vector by multiplying them pre matrix by this weights parameter, which is divided by the square of the dimensions.
그리고 우리는 사전 행렬에 이 가중치 매개변수를 곱하여 이 쿼리 벡터를 계산합니다. 이 가중치 매개변수는 차원의 제곱으로 나뉩니다.
And now we're going to make a global query vector.
이제 전역 쿼리 벡터를 만들어 보겠습니다.
So before this was like our attention scores, we're going to create this global query vector by multiplying element wise.
따라서 이것이 주의 점수와 같기 전에 요소별 곱셈을 통해 이 전역 쿼리 벡터를 생성하겠습니다.
So we pull the learned attention with the query matrix to create q the global query vectors, which is this is saying it's the summation of element wise multiplication of the two vectors, or the attention vector multiplied by the query vector.
따라서 우리는 쿼리 행렬을 사용하여 학습된 Attention을 끌어 전역 쿼리 벡터를 생성합니다. 즉, 두 벡터의 요소별 곱셈의 합, 즉 Attention 벡터에 쿼리 벡터를 곱한 것입니다.
The query matrix and then efficient additive attention output.
쿼리 행렬과 효율적인 추가 주의 출력입니다.
It's performed element wise multiplication between the key matrix K and global query vector q. So time complexity is N by D for this step, rather than N squared by D or N by D squared.
키 행렬 K와 전역 쿼리 벡터 q 사이의 요소별 곱셈이 수행됩니다. 따라서 이 단계의 시간 복잡도는 N 제곱 D 또는 N X D 제곱이 아니라 N x D입니다.
And so to you perform linear transformation tea.
그래서 당신은 선형 변환 차를 수행합니다.
This is how we retain that missing matrix that we didn't include. And then we add a normalized query matrix.
이것이 우리가 포함하지 않은 누락된 행렬을 유지하는 방법입니다. 그런 다음 정규화된 쿼리 행렬을 추가합니다.
Q hat. So,
Q 모자. 그래서,
what this is doing is we've taken the E matrix and multiply by this global query vector. And because it's a vector, it will multiply faster than another matrix.
이것이 하는 일은 E 행렬을 취하고 이 전역 쿼리 벡터를 곱하는 것입니다. 그리고 벡터이기 때문에 다른 행렬보다 빠르게 곱할 것입니다.
And then we do the linear transformation to learn that missing interaction on that. And then we add that as a term to the great matrix, because we've included in that linear transformation, the impact of the value to the overall system.
그런 다음 선형 변환을 수행하여 누락된 상호 작용을 학습합니다. 그런 다음 이를 거대한 행렬의 용어로 추가합니다. 왜냐하면 우리는 선형 변환에 값이 전체 시스템에 미치는 영향을 포함시켰기 때문입니다.
So now there's a more visual approach of these different.
이제 이러한 차이점에 대한 보다 시각적인 접근 방식이 있습니다.
Methods that I described earlier. So first is the general self attention. It's the three matrix transpose one.
앞서 설명한 방법입니다. 첫 번째는 일반적인 자기 관심입니다. 그것은 3개의 행렬 전치 1입니다.
Multiply the two together.
둘을 곱해 보세요.
And then run a soft max.
그런 다음 소프트 최대값을 실행합니다.
And then multiply by the values. And then use your linear layer to create your output.
그런 다음 값을 곱하십시오. 그런 다음 선형 레이어를 사용하여 출력을 만듭니다.
The most sufferable self attention is the element wise on the Q matrix, then do the multiplication and pool them and then multiply by the values.
가장 고통스러운 자기 주의는 Q 행렬의 요소별입니다. 그런 다음 곱셈을 수행하고 이를 풀링한 다음 값을 곱합니다.
The efficient additive attention.
효율적인 첨가주의.
As you include the attention step in that element wise vector.
해당 요소별 벡터에 주의 단계를 포함시키면 됩니다.
Then you're just summing them.
그런 다음 그것들을 합산하면 됩니다.
And then you're multiplying by K.
그리고 K를 곱합니다.
And doing that transformation.
그리고 그 변화를 수행합니다.
And also including a normalization. So, if we look at the complexity of each self attention is usually spatial dimensions on spatial dimensions and it's N by N transpose intention uses on future dimensions and it's D by D.
또한 정규화도 포함됩니다. 따라서 각 self attention의 복잡성을 살펴보면 일반적으로 공간 차원의 공간 차원이고 미래 차원에서 N x N 전치 의도 사용과 D x D입니다.
And then separate will uses the element wise operations to improve efficiency and efficient.
그런 다음 분리는 요소별 작업을 사용하여 효율성과 효율성을 향상시킵니다.
Added of attention takes a step further with smaller operations being something.
더 작은 작업이 중요해지면서 관심이 한 단계 더 발전했습니다.
So the swift quarter encoder is like, yeah, so we've talked about like how the attention scores are calculated and how.
Swift Quarter 인코더는 예, 그래서 우리는 주의 점수가 어떻게 계산되는지, 어떻게 계산되는지에 대해 이야기했습니다.
And how the transformer learns, but now we want to talk about the general architecture similar to the previous paper. If all is this four stages.
그리고 변환기가 어떻게 학습하는지, 이제 우리는 이전 논문과 유사한 일반적인 아키텍처에 대해 이야기하고 싶습니다. 이게 다 4단계라면.
Where the model is decreasing at the same rate, size of the input image by four, then by eight, then by 16 by 32.
모델이 동일한 비율로 감소하는 경우 입력 이미지의 크기는 4배, 8배, 16배 32배로 감소합니다.
And you feed it into the convolutional encoder, then you feed it into a swift, a former block, and then you down sample it by two.
그리고 이를 컨볼루셔널 인코더에 입력한 다음 이전 블록인 Swift에 입력한 다음 2씩 다운 샘플링합니다.
And then you just repeat for those 4 stages.
그런 다음 해당 4단계를 반복하면 됩니다.
Each of the swift former encoders has this local representation, which is by the depth wise convolutions 3 by 3 convolution and a 1 by 1 convolution.
Swift 이전 인코더 각각은 깊이별 컨볼루션 3x3 컨볼루션 및 1x1 컨볼루션에 의한 로컬 표현을 갖습니다.
Then we take that efficient additive attention layer that we explained earlier, then we have our linear transformation.
그런 다음 앞서 설명한 효율적인 추가 주의 레이어를 사용하여 선형 변환을 수행합니다.
And each common evolution encoder is the depth wise convolution normalization by 1 convolution.
그리고 각각의 공통 진화 인코더는 1 컨볼루션에 의한 깊이별 컨볼루션 정규화입니다.
The activation layer, which is the gilu and the convo.
Gilu와 Convo인 활성화 계층입니다.
So here are the results.
결과는 다음과 같습니다.
So swift former is a hybrid between the convalescent and trans transformers.
따라서 스위프트 포머는 회복기 트랜스포머와 트랜스 트랜스포머 사이의 하이브리드입니다.
And it has less parameters.
그리고 매개변수가 더 적습니다.
Then most than some of the other hybrid approaches, but it has better accuracy.
그런 다음 다른 하이브리드 접근 방식보다 대부분 정확하지만 정확도가 더 높습니다.
And it has a lower latency. In this case, I don't see.
그리고 대기 시간이 더 짧습니다. 이 경우에는 보이지 않습니다.
The latency being the biggest issue just in general practice because we're talking in milliseconds. So in any performance setting,
대기 시간은 밀리초 단위로 이야기하기 때문에 일반적으로 가장 큰 문제입니다. 따라서 어떤 성능 설정에서도
prediction, if you're doing something in real time, it just has to be like 60 frames a second. I think it's like the minimum.
예측, 실시간으로 무언가를 한다면 초당 60프레임 정도여야 합니다. 최소한의 수준인 것 같아요.
And so anything like realistically under a latency of 10 milliseconds is going to achieve that goal. The bigger thing is the throughput.
따라서 현실적으로 10밀리초 미만의 지연 시간이면 그 목표를 달성할 수 있습니다. 더 큰 것은 처리량입니다.
It has a better throughput than all of the other hybrid approaches.
다른 모든 하이브리드 접근 방식보다 처리량이 더 좋습니다.
Not necessarily not all the other transformer ones, but all the other hybrids in most cases.
반드시 다른 모든 변압기가 필요한 것은 아니지만 대부분의 경우 다른 모든 하이브리드가 필요합니다.
And the throughput here is just your training speed. So the trains faster.
여기서 처리량은 단지 훈련 속도일 뿐입니다. 그래서 기차가 더 빨라요.
And so even though it has less operations that it has to do.
따라서 해야 할 작업이 적더라도 마찬가지입니다.
If the throughput is like slower, like for instance in DIT.
예를 들어 DIT와 같이 처리량이 느린 경우.
dash T in the second block there.
두 번째 블록에 T를 대시하세요.
It has a higher throughput even though it has
있음에도 불구하고 처리량이 더 높습니다.
more
더
like computations that it has to do. So like in that case,
해야 할 계산과 같습니다. 그러니까 그 경우처럼,
you're still going to spend a longer time training, even though it is
당신은 훈련에 더 오랜 시간을 소비하게 될 것입니다.
technically faster is due to that it likely has to train more times
기술적으로 더 빠른 것은 더 많은 시간을 훈련해야 하기 때문입니다.
or more epochs, but you will get a better result with us with form.
또는 더 많은 시대가 필요하지만 양식을 통해 더 나은 결과를 얻을 수 있습니다.
Next, it's detection and image segmentation. So similar to the last paper.
다음으로는 탐지와 이미지 분할입니다. 지난번 논문과 비슷해요.
These detection instance segmentations are based on bounding boxes
이러한 탐지 인스턴스 분할은 경계 상자를 기반으로 합니다.
on different thresholds and also masks on different thresholds.
다른 임계값에 적용되고 다른 임계값에 마스크도 적용됩니다.
And switch former performs the best of all of them.
그리고 스위치 포머(Switch Former)는 이들 중 최고의 성능을 발휘합니다.
And then they also do on for the semantic. It's the intersection over union.
그리고 그들은 또한 의미론을 수행합니다. 그것은 노동조합을 넘어서는 교차점이다.
Which is the same metric described earlier.
앞서 설명한 것과 동일한 측정항목입니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.